{
    "deck_name": "IK434A",
    "cards": [
        {
            "question": "\"Protection against unauthorized access”/ ”Skydd mot obehörig insyn” [SIS TR50: 2015]",
            "answer": "Confidentiality"
        },
        {
            "question": "\"Protection against unwanted change”/ ”Skydd mot oönskad förändring” [SIS TR50: 2015]",
            "answer": "Integrity"
        },
        {
            "question": "\"Access for a competent person at the right time”/ ”Åtkomst för behörig person vid rätttillfälle” [SIS TR50: 2015]",
            "answer": "Availability"
        },
        {
            "question": "\"Determination of access rights for a user”/ ”Fastställande av åtkomsträttigheter fören användare” [SIS TR50: 2015]",
            "answer": "Authorization (authenticity)"
        },
        {
            "question": "“Provision of technical evidence for the existence of an alleged event or act and itsorigin”/ “Tillhandahållande av teknisk bevisning för förekomsten av en påståddhändelse eller handling och dess ursprung” [SIS TR50: 2015]",
            "answer": "Non-repudiation"
        },
        {
            "question": "The same key is used for both data encryption and data decryption",
            "answer": "Symmetric encryption or \"shared-key encryption\""
        },
        {
            "question": "What is one of the biggest challenges in cryptographic systems?",
            "answer": "Distribution of keys"
        },
        {
            "question": "Here you use two different keys: an open (public) key to encrypt with and your own private key to decrypt",
            "answer": "Asymmetric Encryption (Public-Key Encryption)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Alice sends encrypted content along with an encrypted one-time key (session key) to Bob. Bob decrypts the one-time key using his private key and then decrypts the content with this one-time key",
            "answer": "Hybrid Encryption (Digital Envelope)"
        },
        {
            "question": "A data block that is usually attached to the delivered message",
            "answer": "Digital Signature"
        },
        {
            "question": "How do digital signatures achieve transmitter authentication, message integrity, and non-repudiation?",
            "answer": "Digital signatures ensure transmitter authentication by linking the message uniquely to the owner's private key, maintain message integrity by detecting any alterations through hash verification, and provide non-repudiation by irrefutably proving the sender's acknowledgment and consent."
        },
        {
            "question": "Facilitates secure data sharing over networks like the Internet using asymmetric encryption. Each user's public key is associated with their credentials via a digital certificate",
            "answer": "Public Key Infrastructure (PKI)"
        },
        {
            "question": "The _ is an electronic document used to prove that the user owns a public key used in cryptography and to prove the identity",
            "answer": "(Digital) Certificate"
        },
        {
            "question": "A Digital Certificate is issued by an official and third-party trusted _",
            "answer": "Certificate Authority (CA)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Symantec, RapidSSL, Comodo, and GeoTrust are examples of _",
            "answer": "Certificate Authorities (CAs)"
        },
        {
            "question": "To prevent this type of attack, the company must timestamp or number the messages",
            "answer": "Replay Attack"
        },
        {
            "question": "There are different types of _. One of them is by using KeyLoggers",
            "answer": "Man-In-The-Middle Attack (MITM Attack)"
        },
        {
            "question": "A condition at an interface under which more input can be placed into a buffer or data holding area than capacity allocated, overwriting other information. Attackers exploit such a condition to crash a system or to insert specially crafted code that allows them to gain control of the system",
            "answer": "Buffer Overflow\n"
        },
        {
            "question": "A method of overloading a predefined amount of space in a buffer, which can potentially overwrite and corrupt data in memory",
            "answer": "Buffer Overflow Attacks"
        },
        {
            "question": "Is it true that higher-level programming languages are immune to buffer overflow attacks?",
            "answer": "Higher-level programming languages are generally safe from buffer overflow attacks because they do not allow more data to be stored in the buffer than its designated size. These languages prioritize solving the given problem with less emphasis on managing the intricate details of variable interactions. However, a drawback of this approach is the loss of direct access to hardware resources, such as when writing code for device drivers. In contrast, the C language provides a balance by offering both low- and high-level controls, allowing for more direct hardware manipulation while also supporting higher-level programming constructs"
        },
        {
            "question": "Checking the input before writing it to the buffer (input validation), employing safe-coding techniques, conducting independent code reviews and testing, choosing a higher-level language or using safe libraries, and implementing stack protection mechanisms that identify changes and abort the program as soon as possible are examples of...",
            "answer": "...Buffer Overflow Countermeasures"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the problem with using 'gets(string1);' in a C program?",
            "answer": "The issue with the 'gets' function in C is that it does not check the amount of data entered by the user. If the user inputs more characters than the buffer size allocated for 'string1', the buffer overflows. This happens because 'gets' does not limit the input to the buffer's capacity in C, causing excess data to spill into adjacent memory. This can lead to serious security vulnerabilities and instability in C programs"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why are higher-level languages such as C#, Java, Python, etc., often referred to as 'managed languages'?",
            "answer": "These languages are termed 'managed' because they operate within a specific runtime environment that translates an intermediate language (such as CIL for C# and Bytecode for Java) into machine instructions. This runtime environment takes on the responsibility of managing crucial aspects like memory allocation, security, and other system-level features, thus providing an additional layer of abstraction and control compared to lower-level languages"
        },
        {
            "question": "A program that is inserted into a system, usually covertly, with the intent of compromising the confidentiality, integrity, or availability of the victim’s data applications, or operating system orof otherwise annoying or disrupting the victim",
            "answer": "Malicious Software (Malware)"
        },
        {
            "question": "A computer program that can copy itself and infect a computer without permission or knowledge of the user. A _ might corrupt or delete data on a computer, use email programs to spread itself to other computers, or even erase everything on a hard disk",
            "answer": "Virus\n"
        },
        {
            "question": "Describes the various ways malware spreads to infect other systems. Examples include email attachments, malicious websites, and network vulnerabilities",
            "answer": "Propagation Methods (Propagation)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Details the types of harm caused by malware, such as data corruption, information theft, system performance degradation, and unauthorized system access",
            "answer": "Impact and Payload (Harm/payload)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Explains how malware activates itself within a system, which can include exploiting software vulnerabilities, deceiving users into installing it, or being triggered by specific conditions",
            "answer": "Activation Mechanisms (Activation)"
        },
        {
            "question": "Outlines how malware avoids detection and removal by security software. This includes techniques like rootkits, polymorphism, and obfuscation",
            "answer": "Evasion Techniques (Stealth)"
        },
        {
            "question": "_ are sophisticated cyber threats that utilize a combination of malware types and attack vectors. They are designed to exploit multiple vulnerabilities and often combine the characteristics of viruses, worms, and Trojans to maximize damage and spread rapidly",
            "answer": "Blended Attacks"
        },
        {
            "question": "Name four activation mechanisms for malware",
            "answer": "Setup and installer programs, attached files, macros, and autorun features"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the type of virus that utilizes the scripting function inside a document, like Microsoft Word, to perform malicious activities? Microsoft has developed a _ Virus Protection to detect suspected documents",
            "answer": "Macro Virus (Macros)"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the feature of an operating system that allows for automatic execution of programs, which a threat actor might target to execute a virus?",
            "answer": "Autorun. Examples include autoexec.bat in DOS/command prompt environments or the Task Scheduler in Windows"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does it mean when a virus is appended to a program?",
            "answer": "When a virus is appended to a program, it means that the virus code is attached to the end of the program file. Each time the program is executed, the virus code runs first, completes its task, and then control is transferred back to the original program"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does it mean when a virus is surrounding a program?",
            "answer": "A virus that surrounds a program takes control both before and after the program's execution. This means the virus can perform its actions before the program starts and after it finishes, effectively encasing the program's execution within its control"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does it mean when a virus is integrated into a program?",
            "answer": "Integration of a virus into a program involves inserting the virus code into the program's code. This requires the virus developer to understand the program's structure to strategically place the virus code. The virus and program code become intermingled, making it harder to separate the virus from the program without damaging the latter"
        },
        {
            "question": "A self-replicating, self-propagating, self-contained program that uses networking mechanisms to spread itself",
            "answer": "Worm"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the main difference between a worm and a virus?",
            "answer": "The main difference lies in their method of propagation. A worm is a standalone malware that replicates itself and spreads independently across networks without requiring any host program. On the other hand, a virus depends on attaching itself to a host program or file and spreads by modifying other programs with its own code. While both can cause similar types of damage, their modes of transmission and propagation are distinct"
        },
        {
            "question": "A recognizable, distinguishing pattern associated with an attack, such as a binary string in a virus or a particular set of keystrokes used to gain an unauthorized access to a system",
            "answer": "Virus Signature"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is typically used to uniquely identify a virus, which can be, for example, a hash calculated on a part of the virus code that is unique to the virus, or a hash based on the behavior of the virus (such as when a program performs specific actions X, Y, and Z)?",
            "answer": "Virus Signature. A virus signature is a unique string of bytes or a pattern that antivirus software uses to identify and detect specific viruses. It can be derived from a unique part of the virus code or from the characteristic behaviors exhibited by the virus, such as performing specific actions or sequences of actions within a system"
        },
        {
            "question": "Describe a Polymorphic Virus",
            "answer": "A polymorphic virus is a type of malware that can change its observable characteristics, such as its code, signature, or encryption, each time it infects a new system. This is achieved by randomly repositioning, encrypting, or otherwise altering its code without changing the fundamental functionality of the virus. Despite the varying appearance, the underlying attack code remains the same. This ability to morph makes it challenging for antivirus programs to detect and match the virus to signatures saved in their database, as the virus presents differently in each iteration"
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of virus encrypts its body with a variable key every time it replicates, uses a decryptor to execute the encrypted virus body in the targeted program, and can be identified through its consistent decryptor (Virus Signature)?",
            "answer": "Encrypted Virus. This type of virus encrypts its main body or payload with a different key upon each infection, making its appearance variable and harder to detect by antivirus programs. To execute, it uses a small static decryptor component, which remains the same across infections. This decryptor decrypts the virus body so it can execute within the target program. It is this consistent decryptor part that can be used as a virus signature for antivirus software to detect and identify the encrypted virus"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are some key security requirements for relational databases?",
            "answer": "Database Integrity, Element Integrity, Auditability, Access Control, User Authentication, and Availability"
        },
        {
            "question": "In relational databases, data should be safeguarded against physical problems (e.g., power failures), necessitating regular backups. Additionally, ensuring that modifications to the value of one field do not affect other fields are examples of...",
            "answer": "...Data Integrity"
        },
        {
            "question": "In relational databases, the data should be correct and the DBMS performs the following actions to ensure _: Field checks, access control, and change logs",
            "answer": "Element Integrity\n"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does 'Auditability' mean in the context of relational databases?",
            "answer": "Auditability in relational databases refers to the capability to track, record, and examine all database activities, especially those related to data access and modification. This includes maintaining detailed logs that capture which user performed what action and at what time. It also involves monitoring and recording incremental access to sensitive data. Auditability is crucial for ensuring security, compliance with regulations, and for forensic analysis in case of security breaches or unauthorized activities. It helps in establishing accountability and in maintaining the integrity of the database by providing a transparent and traceable history of all transactions"
        },
        {
            "question": "Describe 'Access Control' in the context of relational databases",
            "answer": "Access Control in relational databases refers to the process of specifying who is allowed to access specific data, and at what level"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the context of relational databases, what security requirement is being referred to when a DBMS authenticates the user before allowing access to the data, and in some cases, performs independent authentication separate from the operating system?",
            "answer": "User Authentication. This security requirement involves verifying the identity of users before granting them access to the database. User Authentication ensures that only authorized individuals can access the database, thereby protecting sensitive data from unauthorized access"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the context of relational databases, what security requirement is being referred to when it's stated that the DBMS should be consistently available to users and allow them access to the data for which they are authorized?",
            "answer": "Availability. This security requirement emphasizes the importance of the database being accessible and operational when needed by authorized users"
        },
        {
            "question": "Describe 'Integrity' in the context of CIA and DBMS",
            "answer": "Integrity ensures the accuracy and consistency of data both at the individual element level and across the entire database. It involves mechanisms to prevent unauthorized data modification"
        },
        {
            "question": "Describe 'Confidentiality' in the context of CIA and DBMS",
            "answer": "Confidentiality pertains to controlling access to sensitive data within the database. The key challenge is in preventing indirect access or inference, where unauthorized users might glean sensitive information without direct access to the database"
        },
        {
            "question": "Describe 'Availability' in the context of CIA and DBMS",
            "answer": "Availability focuses on ensuring that authorized users have reliable access to the database, important due to the shared nature of database access. It addresses challenges like concurrent user access, which could impact database performance and availability"
        },
        {
            "question": "You notice the string ' OR 1=1;-- in your database login logs. What is this, and what does it imply?",
            "answer": "This string is indicative of a SQL Injection (SQLi) attempt, where a threat actor is trying to manipulate the SQL query. In this context, the ' OR 1=1;-- is an injection technique used to alter the query logic. It effectively changes the query to return true for all records (since 1=1 is always true), bypassing standard authentication checks. The -- at the end is a comment symbol in SQL, which makes the database ignore the rest of the query, further aiding in the exploitation. This type of attack is a serious security concern and suggests vulnerabilities in the input validation of the database system"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are some countermeasures against SQL Injection (SQLi)?",
            "answer": "Input Type Checking, Parametrized Queries, and Testing for SQLi"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the difference between Black-box testing and White-box testing?",
            "answer": "Black-box testing focuses on examining the functionality of the software without any knowledge of its internal code structure. It's like testing a machine only by its inputs and outputs. In contrast, White-box testing involves a thorough understanding and examination of the software's internal logic and code structure. This approach is akin to testing a machine by understanding and inspecting its internal workings. While Black-box testing evaluates the software from the user's perspective, White-box testing delves deeper into the code for a more technical analysis"
        },
        {
            "question": "Prevent (malicious) developers from attempting to hide something in a module of the system (e.g. backdoor)",
            "answer": "Independent Testing"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the practice where a specialized team attempts to breach system security, using methods that closely mimic real-world attacker tactics, and is only as secure as the scope of the tests performed?",
            "answer": "Penetration Testing. This is a security exercise where a team of skilled testers, often known as ethical hackers, deliberately tries to hack into a system's defenses"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term for a network where devices such as computers and printers communicate within a controlled environment?\n",
            "answer": "Local Area Network (LAN). A LAN is a network that connects devices in a limited area, such as a home, office, or school, allowing for controlled and efficient communication among them"
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of network is characterized by endpoints that are scattered and far from each other, making it more challenging to protect data outside of a local network?",
            "answer": "Wide Area Network (WAN). A WAN covers a large geographic area, connecting devices that are often distant from each other. Due to its extensive reach beyond local networks, it presents unique challenges in terms of data protection and security management"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the layers in the ISO/OSI reference model?",
            "answer": "Application - Presentation - Session - Transport - Network - Data Link - Physical"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the layers in the Internet reference model?",
            "answer": "Application (protocols like HTTP, SMTP, SSH - Transport (protocols such as TCP/UDP) - Internet (IP protocols like IPv4/IPv6) - Data Link (technologies like 802.x, PPP, SLIP)"
        },
        {
            "question": "When and where is control information added in the context of network communication?",
            "answer": "In network communication, control information is added at the bottom layers, particularly in the Data Link and Network layers of the OSI model. This control information is encapsulated in the form of headers and trailers. Headers are added at the beginning of data packets, containing information necessary for routing and delivering the packet. Trailers are added at the end, often containing error-checking data. This process is crucial for the proper management and transmission of data across the network"
        },
        {
            "question": "Is it true or false that physical transmission media are harder to intercept but more expensive to set up than wireless ones?",
            "answer": "True. Physical transmission media, like wired networks, are generally harder to intercept due to their physical nature, requiring physical access for interception. However, they are typically more expensive and labor-intensive to set up compared to wireless networks, which require less physical infrastructure"
        },
        {
            "question": "Name some types of transmission media",
            "answer": "Common types of transmission media include Wire (such as twisted pair and coaxial cables), Optical fiber, Microwave, Wireless (including radio and WiFi), and Satellite"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are some vulnerabilities associated with wired networks, particularly related to packet transmission and interception?",
            "answer": "Wired networks face several vulnerabilities such as packet sniffing and Man-in-the-Middle (MITM) attacks. Packet sniffing involves setting the LAN card into a Monitor (Promiscuous) mode, where the MAC address is ignored and all packets on the network are received. In this mode, an attacker can intercept and analyze packets passing through the network. Additionally, intercepted packets can be resent in a Man-in-the-Middle attack, where the attacker secretly intercepts and possibly alters the communication between two parties who believe they are directly communicating with each other"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a key vulnerability of wired networks involving electromagnetic radiation, and how can it be exploited by an intruder?",
            "answer": "A significant vulnerability of wired networks is the emission of weak electromagnetic radiations from the wires. An intruder can exploit this by using a process called inductance to tap into a wire and read the radiated signals without making physical contact with the cable. Essentially, the intruder sets up an antenna close to the cable to pick up the radiations passing through it, enabling them to intercept the data transmitted over the wire"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a vulnerability in wired networks involving direct interference with the physical cable, and how is it executed?",
            "answer": "A notable vulnerability in wired networks is cable splicing or cable tapping. This involves directly cutting the cable and splicing in a secondary cable that receives a copy of all signals traveling along the primary cable. Special devices, known as vampire taps, can be used to 'bite' into the cable and intercept communications. This method allows an intruder to access the data flow without disrupting the network's normal operation"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the vulnerabilities associated with optical fiber networks, and why is physical tapping considered challenging?",
            "answer": "Optical fiber networks are resistant to many conventional tapping methods due to their reliance on light rather than electricity for signal transmission. Physical tapping of optical fibers is difficult because the entire network requires careful tuning each time a connection is made, making unauthorized tapping noticeable. It requires high skill and expensive equipment. Additionally, since the signal is transmitted through light, there are no electromagnetic radiations, making inductance attacks ineffective"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are some key vulnerabilities associated with microwave transmission in networking?",
            "answer": "Microwave transmission is particularly vulnerable due to its dependence on line-of-sight locations. Since signals are broadcasted through the air, they are more accessible to hackers. The signal must be repeated approximately every 50 kilometers, making it exposed to interception along its transmission path. Intruders can potentially place their own receivers near the intended destination to intercept or capture the entire communication"
        },
        {
            "question": "Why are wireless (WiFi) networks considered less secure compared to wired networks, and what makes security protocols essential for WiFi?",
            "answer": "Wireless (WiFi) networks are generally considered less secure than wired ones because WiFi signals propagate radially and can diffuse through obstacles, allowing for easier unauthorized access. For instance, while browsing the internet from one room, an attacker could potentially target your network from another location. Due to this exposure risk, WiFi networks require robust security protocols to protect against unauthorized access and ensure data safety"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are some reasons that make a network vulnerable to interception?",
            "answer": "Networks become vulnerable to interception due to several factors: Anonymity, which obscures the identity of attackers; numerous potential points of attack; the shared nature of network resources; system complexity, which can create security gaps; an unknown perimeter, making it hard to define and secure all entry points; and an unknown path of data transmission, which can be exploited"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are some common network attacks, and how do they operate?",
            "answer": "Common network attacks include Port-Scanning, such as using an Nmap scanner, which analyzes running services on a target machine to gather information about service versions. This can reveal potential exploits. Another example is (Distributed) Denial of Services Attacks (DDoS), where the target system is overwhelmed with traffic to disrupt its normal operations, often rendering it inaccessible to legitimate users"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a Denial of Service (DoS) attack, and what is its primary objective?",
            "answer": "A Denial of Service (DoS) attack is a cyber-attack where the perpetrator aims to make a machine or network resource unavailable to its intended users. The attack typically floods the target with excessive requests, overwhelming the system and preventing it from servicing legitimate users, thus failing to fulfill its duties"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the main categories of DoS attacks?",
            "answer": "DoS attacks can take various forms, including Flooding (like Ping of Death, Smurf – though these are rather outdated) where the attacker sends a massive number of packets, overwhelming the victim’s bandwidth capacity, and Resource Exhausting attacks that aim to deplete the victim's resources like CPU or RAM, often exploiting software bugs or design deficiencies"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are other categories of DoS attacks?",
            "answer": "Other categories include Vulnerabilities Exploit, where attacks cause system crashes, and Physical Disconnection, involving cutting or detaching cables to interrupt a connection. Additionally, Frequencies Jamming attacks disrupt communication by transmitting high-range signals, especially in wireless mediums"
        },
        {
            "question": "How does a Distributed Denial of Service (DDoS) attack differ from a standard DoS attack?",
            "answer": "DDoS attacks are an evolution of DoS attacks with similar principles of overloading the victim. The main difference is the use of a large number of machines, often coordinated, to execute the attack, making it more complex and challenging to counteract"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a DDoS Botnet, and how does it function?",
            "answer": "A DDoS Botnet is a network of compromised machines, or 'bots', controlled by a coordinator known as the botmaster. These bots, often infected with malicious code like trojan horses, work in parallel against a victim. The botmaster can send different commands to each bot, allowing a diverse range of attacks and making defense more difficult due to the sheer number of attack sources and their varied nature"
        },
        {
            "question": "How are botnets created through bot recruitment, and what are the two main methods to infect user computers?",
            "answer": "Botnets are formed through bot recruitment by infecting user computers. The two main methods are Drive-by downloads, which involve attackers finding a popular website with an exploitable vulnerability, and Emails, where attackers send large batches of spam emails containing malicious code in documents or PDFs"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the initial steps in counteracting a DDoS attack?",
            "answer": "The first step in DDoS countermeasures is to identify the nature of the attack. If the attack exploits specific vulnerabilities, identifying and fixing them is crucial. Understanding the attack type helps in devising effective countermeasures"
        },
        {
            "question": "What strategies can be employed to mitigate targeted DDoS attacks?",
            "answer": "For targeted DDoS attacks, strategies include increasing the number of servers, temporarily shutting down targeted services, and, in the case of flooding attacks, identifying and blacklisting specific IP address ranges. Increasing bandwidth and resources is also advisable to cope with the excess traffic"
        },
        {
            "question": "How can DDoS Protection vendors be useful in countering DDoS attacks?",
            "answer": "DDoS Protection vendors act as a middleware between users and the company, providing specialized defense against DDoS attacks. Outsourcing to these vendors is often more cost-effective than in-house solutions, as hiring security experts can be expensive. They offer expertise and resources specifically tailored to mitigate DDoS risks"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is one of the most significant DDoS attacks in history?",
            "answer": "One of the most known DDoS attacks in history targeted GitHub on Feb. 28, 2018. The attack generated 1.35 terabits per second of traffic, making it one of the largest of its kind. GitHub traced the traffic back to over a thousand different autonomous systems across tens of thousands of unique endpoints"
        },
        {
            "question": "Good for encrypting network traffic",
            "answer": "Symmetric cryptography"
        },
        {
            "question": "Good for exchanging encryption keys",
            "answer": "Assymetric cryptography"
        },
        {
            "question": "Encryption between two hosts",
            "answer": "Linked Encryption\n"
        },
        {
            "question": "Encryption between two applications (encryption from the beginning at the Application Layer)",
            "answer": "End-to-End Encryption\n"
        },
        {
            "question": "_ is an approach that encrypts and decrypt sall traffic at each network routing point (network switch, ornode) until arrival at its final destination",
            "answer": "Link Encyption\n"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the advantages of using Link Encryption in network communications?",
            "answer": "The pros of Link Encryption include complete encryption of all data transmitted, encompassing not only the content but also headers, addresses, and routing information. It operates automatically at a lower layer in the OSI model, meaning users don’t need to take any action to initiate it, ensuring seamless security throughout the data transmission process"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the disadvantages of using Link Encryption in network communications?",
            "answer": "The cons of Link Encryption involve complex key distribution and management. Each hop in the network requires a key, and these keys must be regularly updated, adding to the administrative overhead. Furthermore, since packets are decrypted at each hop, this creates multiple points of vulnerability, potentially exposing data to interception or tampering at these intermediate points"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the benefits of using End-to-End Encryption in network communications?",
            "answer": "End-to-End Encryption offers more control and flexibility to the user, allowing the choice of what to encrypt and the encryption methods used. It provides finer granularity in functionality, as each application or user can select their encryption configurations. Additionally, intermediate hop computers in the network don’t require decryption keys for each packet, which simplifies key management and enhances security for the data content"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the drawbacks of using End-to-End Encryption in network communications?",
            "answer": "The main drawback of End-to-End Encryption is that it does not encrypt the headers, addresses, and routing information. This means that while the content of the communication is secure, the metadata, which can reveal information like sender, receiver, and data paths, is not protected and can be potentially accessed or analyzed by external entities"
        },
        {
            "question": "What technology provides users with the feeling of being on a private network even when they are part of a public network, often achieved through the use of Link Encryption?",
            "answer": "Virtual Private Network (VPN). A VPN creates a secure and encrypted connection over a public network, giving users the experience of being on a private network. It utilizes link encryption to protect the data as it travels through the public network, ensuring privacy and security for the users' communications"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is one of the challenges associated with using a Virtual Private Network (VPN)?",
            "answer": "A key challenge with VPNs is the secure management and storage of private keys. These keys must be safely stored at both ends of the VPN connection to ensure secure communication. If these keys are compromised or improperly managed, it can lead to vulnerabilities in the VPN's security, potentially allowing unauthorized access to the encrypted data"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the context of internet usage predominantly through browsers, what is fundamental for protecting personal information, messages, and credit card details?",
            "answer": "Browser Encryption. It is essential for safeguarding sensitive data during online interactions. Browser encryption secures the data transmitted between the user's browser and the web servers, ensuring that personal information, messages, and credit card details are protected from interception or unauthorized access"
        },
        {
            "question": "_ is the standard protocol to securely issue commands through a remote shell",
            "answer": "Secure Shell (SSH)"
        },
        {
            "question": "When needing secure communication over a network, should you use SSH or Telnet?",
            "answer": "Secure Shell (SSH) should be used instead of Telnet for secure communications. SSH replaced Telnet due to its enhanced security features. Telnet transmits all data, including sensitive information, in plain text, making it vulnerable to eavesdropping and Man-in-the-Middle (MitM) attacks, where an attacker could intercept and tamper with the transmitted data. SSH, on the other hand, encrypts the data transmitted over the network, providing a much more secure communication channel"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which security protocol started as Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) in the mid-1990s, originally designed by Netscape, to protect communications between a web browser and a server?",
            "answer": "Transport Layer Security (TLS)"
        },
        {
            "question": "HTTPS (Hypertext Transfer Protocol Secure) employs which security protocol to secure communications, operating at the Transport layer in the ISO/OSI model, functioning between the Application layer and Network layer, and providing server/client authentication as well as an encrypted channel between the two endpoints?",
            "answer": "TLS (Transport Layer Security)"
        },
        {
            "question": "This handshake defines how interaction flow happensbetween actors",
            "answer": "TLS/SSL Handshake\n"
        },
        {
            "question": "During the handshake, client and server need to decide what cryptographic algorithms they will use to encrypt communications from that moment on",
            "answer": "Cipher Suite (or Cipher Block)"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a potential vulnerability in the TLS handshake process that could be exploited by attackers?",
            "answer": "A vulnerability in the TLS handshake process is related to the validation of the server's certificate. An attacker could exploit this by orchestrating a Man-in-the-Middle (MitM) attack in the following manner: they could redirect communication to a fake website and then forge a fake certificate with a different set of private/public keys. This could deceive the user into thinking they are communicating with a legitimate server, potentially leading to the disclosure of sensitive information"
        },
        {
            "question": "Is it true or false that modern browsers autonomously verify the validity of a server's certificate and are most of the time able to warn the user if someone is impersonating the real server?",
            "answer": "True. Modern web browsers are designed to automatically check the validity of a server's certificate. If they detect any discrepancies or issues, such as a certificate not matching the domain name or being expired, they typically warn the user of potential risks, such as the possibility of a server impersonation or a Man-in-the-Middle attack"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term for a device that filters and regulates inbound and outbound network traffic based on rules set by the network administrator, often being a dedicated device with its own OS, memory, and network cards, where performance is a critical factor?",
            "answer": "Firewall. A firewall acts as a security gatekeeper, controlling and monitoring the network traffic that enters and leaves a network. It enforces security policies as defined by the network administrator. Being a dedicated device, it typically includes its own operating system, memory, and network interfaces, and is designed to perform efficiently to maintain network security without impeding traffic flow"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the two schools of thought regarding a firewall's default behavior and their respective philosophies?",
            "answer": "The two primary approaches to a firewall's default behavior are 'Default Permit' and 'Default Deny'. The 'Default Permit' approach dictates that all behaviors should be allowed except those explicitly forbidden. Conversely, the 'Default Deny' philosophy asserts that only explicitly permitted behaviors should be allowed, and everything else should be forbidden. These differing strategies reflect a balance between accessibility and security in network management"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a simple yet effective type of firewall that allows or discards each packet based on predefined rules, often requiring extensive time to define detailed rules, and is particularly useful for denying communications over specific ports?",
            "answer": "Packet Filtering Gateway. This type of firewall operates by examining each incoming and outgoing packet and deciding whether to allow or block it based on a set of predefined rules. While it can be effective, especially for blocking specific ports, setting up a packet filtering gateway often requires considerable effort to define detailed and comprehensive rules"
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of firewall analyzes packets in a broader context rather than on a packet-by-packet basis, and can detect patterns such as repeated port connection attempts from the same IP address, which might indicate a port scan?",
            "answer": "Stateful Inspection Firewall. This firewall goes beyond simple packet filtering by examining the context and state of packets. It doesn't just look at individual packets in isolation but also considers the history of network connections and data flows. This ability allows it to identify patterns that could suggest malicious activities, like a port scan, making it more sophisticated and effective in detecting complex threats"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a sophisticated type of firewall that combines features of previous types, analyzes traffic as thoroughly as possible, and is complex to program and manage due to the need for detailed analysis of data flow?",
            "answer": "Guard. A Guard is a comprehensive and sophisticated firewall that integrates various functionalities of previous firewall types. It is designed to analyze network traffic exhaustively, which makes it complex to program and manage. Its thorough approach to data flow analysis ensures high-level security but requires significant time and expertise to operate effectively"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term for the type of firewall used by small businesses and home users, which emulates many features of more comprehensive firewalls but is software-based and primarily protects only the computer on which it is installed?",
            "answer": "Personal Firewalls. These are software-based firewalls designed for small businesses and home users who may not be able to afford more elaborate firewall systems. Personal firewalls emulate many behaviors of advanced firewalls but are limited to protecting the individual computer on which they are installed, rather than an entire network"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the name of the security system that continuously monitors the network for suspicious activities, acting like a smoke detector by triggering an alarm when such activities are detected?",
            "answer": "Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS). IDS are designed to constantly scan and analyze the network for any signs of suspicious or unauthorized activities. Similar to how a smoke detector sounds an alarm when it detects smoke, an IDS alerts the network administrators or takes predefined actions when it identifies potential security threats or intrusions"
        },
        {
            "question": "While Intrusion Detection Systems (IDS) act like smoke detectors by alerting to potential threats, what is the term for systems that not only detect but also autonomously respond to these threats, like activating a fire-fighting system, by taking actions such as blocking users, blacklisting IP ranges, or cutting off network access?",
            "answer": "Intrusion Prevention Systems (IPS). IPSes are essentially IDSes that have been enhanced with response capabilities. They not only detect potential security breaches but also take proactive measures to mitigate the threat. This can include automatically blocking suspicious users, blacklisting certain IP ranges, or even isolating parts of the network to prevent the spread of the threat"
        },
        {
            "question": "As networks evolve over time with changes like an increase in local devices or expanded online business leading to higher server loads, what is the term for the necessary periodic adjustments and practices applied to ensure smooth network operation?",
            "answer": "Network Management. This term refers to the various techniques and practices employed to maintain and administer a computer network as it changes and grows. Effective network management ensures that the network adapts to changes such as an increase in connected devices or a rise in demand on web servers, helping to maintain optimal performance and reliability"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the context of system administration, what is the term for the practice of planning to avoid running a system near its maximum capacity, especially considering potential events like new product launches that could cause severe overloads?",
            "answer": "Capacity Planning. This involves forecasting future system demands and ensuring that the IT infrastructure is scaled appropriately to handle increases in load. It requires administrators to plan in advance for potential high-demand events to prevent system overloads and maintain smooth operation"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term for the technique used in managing online businesses or networked systems where network load is distributed across multiple servers to optimize performance and prevent any single machine from being overwhelmed?",
            "answer": "Load Balancing. This technique involves distributing network or application traffic across multiple servers to ensure no single server bears too much load. Load balancing is crucial for maintaining the efficiency and reliability of an online business or networked system, especially when running on multiple machines"
        },
        {
            "question": "What process do network engineers use, similar to load balancing, to restructure a network by installing new links, increasing connectivity, or rate-limiting traffic by dropping suspicious packets?",
            "answer": "Network Tuning. This involves adjusting and optimizing the network by adding new connections, enhancing existing connectivity, or implementing rate limits and filters to manage traffic flow and enhance security, such as by dropping suspicious packets"
        },
        {
            "question": "Given the limitation of IPv4 regarding the inability to prevent IP spoofing, what is a fundamental issue in network security, where even measures like link encryption cannot fully address the protocol's inherent flaw?",
            "answer": "Network Addressing. The inherent problem in IPv4 is the lack of a mechanism to prevent IP spoofing, where attackers can forge packets with a different IP address. While link encryption can provide a level of security, it does not rectify the fundamental protocol flaw that allows for IP address forgery"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term for the network security technique where routers are set to drop packets involved in a DoS attack, effectively filtering out all traffic from implicated addresses, but which might lead attackers to spoof legitimate sources?",
            "answer": "Shunning. This technique involves configuring network routers to ignore or drop packets from known malicious sources. However, if attackers realize that shunning is in place, they may adapt by spoofing IP addresses from legitimate sources to bypass these filters"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the practice called where an administrator blacklists certain IP addresses to block all incoming traffic from them, or alternatively redirects this traffic to a specific address for analysis?",
            "answer": "Blacklisting and Sinkholing. Blacklisting involves denying all traffic from certain IP addresses deemed malicious. Sinkholing redirects this traffic to a different address where it can be analyzed, allowing for further investigation of malicious activities without impacting the primary network services"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are some key security functions provided by operating systems?",
            "answer": "Availability: Ensuring equal sharing of system resources among users. Interprocess Communication and Synchronization: Managing how different processes interact and coordinate with each other. Protection of Critical System Data: This is achieved through methods like encryption, hardware control, and isolation. Hardware Access: Providing controlled indirect or direct access to hardware components.\nUser Authentication: Implementing security measures such as passwords, biometrics, etc., to verify user identities.\nMemory Protection: Utilizing techniques like paging or segmentation to protect the integrity of memory. Access Control: Regulating who can access what resources within the system."
        },
        {
            "question": "In the context of system security, describe the role and importance of logging, including aspects like what should be logged and how logs are analyzed",
            "answer": "Logging is a reactive control mechanism in system security, crucial for recording activities within the system. It documents which subjects (users or processes) accessed which objects (files, systems, data) and details the time, manner, and context of these interactions. This information is vital for accurately identifying the nature of any incidents, aiding in recovery efforts, and helping to prevent future security breaches. The decision on what data to log should be made during system planning, based on the security requirements of the system. Log analysis can be performed manually, which is often tedious and less reliable, or through automated methods such as intrusion detection systems, which offer more efficient and accurate analysis"
        },
        {
            "question": "In the context of operating systems, what is the term for the technique that abstracts hardware resources for different classes of users, presenting each user with only the resources their class is entitled to use?",
            "answer": "Virtualization. This is a process where the operating system abstracts the underlying hardware resources to create distinct environments for different classes of users. Each user or user group is provided access to a set of resources specific to their needs and permissions, ensuring efficient and secure resource utilization"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the security mechanism that creates a controlled, isolated environment where untested or untrusted programs can run without affecting the host operating system, and typically limits user resources and network access?",
            "answer": "Sandbox. A sandbox is a virtual environment that serves as a security mechanism to separate and isolate processes. It allows for the safe execution of untested or untrusted programs without risking the integrity of the host operating system. Sandboxes often restrict resource usage and disallow network access to maintain security"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term for a security mechanism that acts as a decoy to attract attackers, allowing administrators to monitor malicious activities in real-time to understand attackers’ objectives, tools, techniques, and weaknesses, and plan future defenses accordingly?",
            "answer": "Honeypots. Honeypots are security mechanisms designed to mimic vulnerable systems to attract attackers. They serve as bait to study attackers' methods in a controlled environment. By monitoring these activities, administrators gain insights into attack strategies, which aids in developing more robust security measures for real systems"
        },
        {
            "question": "An attack on the authentication protocol run in which the attacker positions himself in between the claimant and verifier so that he can intercept and alter data traveling between them",
            "answer": "Man-in-the-middle attack (MITM)"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term for a tool, either in the form of hardware or software, that records every keystroke made on a computer? This tool can send the recorded information directly to an attacker or store it for offline analysis, and is capable of capturing passwords, login identities, and any other data typed on the keyboard",
            "answer": "Keyloggers (Keystroke logger). Keyloggers are devices or software programs designed to record all keystrokes made on a computer. They can either transmit this data in real-time to an attacker over a network or save it for later retrieval and analysis. Keyloggers are capable of capturing a wide range of sensitive information, including passwords, login credentials, and other personal data entered via the keyboard"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the term for the type of security vulnerability where a website responds with malicious JavaScript code, which is then executed by the victim's browser, leading to the victim’s cookies being sent to the attacker’s server, allowing the attacker to potentially impersonate the victim and launch further attacks?",
            "answer": "Cross-site scripting (XSS). In an XSS attack, a website inadvertently includes malicious JavaScript in its response to a user request. The victim's browser unknowingly executes this script, which then transmits the victim's cookies or other sensitive data to the attacker. The attacker can use this information to impersonate the victim and carry out additional malicious activities"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are some effective countermeasures to protect against Cross-site scripting (XSS) attacks?",
            "answer": "To counter XSS attacks, several measures can be implemented. Firstly, escaping dynamic content is crucial; this involves encoding user input so that it is treated as data rather than executable code. Secondly, restricting data values, such as setting limits on the type and length of user input, can prevent malicious scripts from being inserted. Lastly, avoiding the execution of inline JavaScript code is advisable; for example, instead of using 'innerHTML' which can render entire HTML markup including scripts, use 'textContent' which safely renders text without executing any embedded code. These strategies collectively reduce the risk of XSS vulnerabilities in web applications."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the email encryption method that operates based on a public key infrastructure similar to SSL and requires obtaining a certificate from a Certificate Authority (CA)?",
            "answer": "S/MIME (Secure/Multipurpose Internet Mail Extensions). It utilizes the X.509 public key infrastructure, paralleling SSL in its mechanism. To secure email communications, a user needs to apply for a digital certificate from a CA, which then allows for the encryption and digital signing of emails, enhancing the security and authenticity of the communication"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the encryption method where users create their own certificates, share them with others, and participate in a 'web of trust' by signing each other’s certificates, thereby each acting as their own Certificate Authority?",
            "answer": "PGP (Pretty Good Privacy). In this system, users generate their own certificates and share their public keys with others. They sign each other's certificates, building a 'web of trust.' The responsibility lies with each user to verify the identity of others they interact with. Users can publish their PGP public keys on social media platforms or public key servers, using this method to authenticate themselves to others and secure their communications"
        }
    ]
}
